Sayeeda Tasmia

Email:

smohammednasir@hawk.iit.edu

Phone: +1 415 405 5275

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/tasmia mohammed/

Address:

300 W, 31st Street, Chicago, IL

Technical Capabilities

- Programming and
 Frameworks:
 Java, J2EE, Python, Spring, Struts, Hibernate
- Web Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, AngularJs, NodeJS, MVC 3, React.
- Operating System: Windows and Linux
- **Database:** MySQL, Oracle 11g, SQL server, MongoDB
- Other Tools and Technologies: SVN (Tortoise), Git, Bugzilla, Bash Scripting and Shell Programming, Web

Achievements

- Oracle Certified Java
 Programmer (Java SE 6).
- Received Spot Award for Best performance at EKA Software Solutions in 2018.
- Received Best Team Award for Louis Dreyfus upgrade project at Eka Software Solutions in 2017

Exploring software development opportunities to add value to a team

Career Snapshot

A motivated individual with in-depth knowledge of languages and development tools, seeking a position in a growth-oriented company where I can contribute my 6 years of IT experience and technical skills to the advantage of the company while having the scope to develop my own skills.

Educational Background

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago	Master of science in Information Technology and Management	Aug 2019 - Present
Visvesvaraya	Bachelor of science in	Aug 2009 Jul 2012
Technological University,	Information Science and	Aug 2008 – Jul 2012 GPA – 7.3/10
Bangalore, India	Engineering	GPA - 7.5/10

Work Experience

EKA Software Solution Senior Software Engineer Jan 2016 – Jul 2019

- Core member of the development team. Worked on various modules like Physical, Planning, Logistics, Financials, and Settlements of Commodity Trading and Risk Management (CTRM) system.
- Developed new features in Physical, Pricing and Logistic modules. Introduced ticketing feature in logistics module. Prepared unit test cases and conducted code reviews. Involved in upgrading the hibernate version to 5.4.1 Final.
- Go-live support by fixing production issues, change requests (CRs) and improving performance.

Tools and Technologies: Java SE 8, JBoss 6 and Apache Struts 1, Hibernate 2, Spring 3, Maven 3.3.9, Oracle DB, PL/SQL developer, Toad.

Clients: Louis-Dreyfus, Providence Grain Solutions, BroadGrain, Sierentz Global Merchants, Tereos, World Energy.

DreamOrbit Softech Pvt Ltd Software Engineer Apr 2015 – Jan 2016

- Designed and developed a Training Management System for US based courier services.
- Extensive use of **AngularJS** for front-end. API calls written in **Ruby on Rails** (RoR) for building modules like Admin, Customer and Driver.

Client: AM-TRAN.

eMudhra Limited Software Developer Mar 2014 – Apr 2015

- Developed a License Management System which involves generation of licenses using Digital Signature Certificates.
- Analyzed the legacy code and optimized component code modules. Solely responsible for coding and implementing new licenses using Spring framework.
 - Involved in preparation of technical documents which is used by the support team. **Tools and Technologies**: Java 7, Spring 3, Hibernate 3, Oracle 11g, Oracle SQL Developer.

Client: Mauritian Government